<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
		<file name="bard-college-dance.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caiapha/Aurora_AddCon/refs/heads/main/core/PHB24/bard-college-dance.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- College of Dance Subclass -->
	<element name="College of Dance" type="Archetype" source="Player’s Handbook Rev. 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_COLLEGE_OF_DANCE">
		<supports>Bard subclass</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Bards of the College of Dance know that the Words of Creation can't be contained within speech or song; the words are uttered by the movements of celestial bodies and flow through the motions of the smallest creatures. These Bards practice a way of being in harmony with the whirling cosmos that emphasizes agility, speed, and grace.</p>	
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_INSPIRING_MOVEMENT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_TANDEM_FOOTWORK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_LEADING_EVASION" />	
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_INSPIRING_MOVEMENT" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_TANDEM_FOOTWORK" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_LEADING_EVASION" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Dazzling Footwork" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook Rev. 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 3rd level, While you aren't wearing armor or wielding a Shield, you gain the following benefits.</p>
			<p><strong>Dance Virtuoso:</strong> you have Advantage on any Charisma (Performance) check you make that involves you dancing.</p>    
			<p><strong>Unarmored Defense:</strong> your base Armor Class equals 10 plus your Dexterity and Charisma modifiers.</p>
			<p><strong>Agile Strikes:</strong> when you expend a use of your Bardic Inspiration as part of an action, a Bonus Action, or a Reaction, you can make one Unarmed Strike as part of that action, Bonus Action, or Reaction.</p>
			<p><strong>Bardic Damage:</strong> you can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack rolls of your Unarmed Strikes. When you deal damage with an Unarmed Strike, you can deal Bludgeoning damage equal to a roll of your Bardic Inspiration die plus your Dexterity modifier, instead of the strike's normal damage. This roll doesn't expend the die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>After each Long Rest, choose one spell list: Arid, Polar, Temperate, Tropical. The Circle Spells are always prepared.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant name="Dance Virtuoso" type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK_DANCE_VIRTUOSO" />
			<grant name="Unarmored Defense" type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK_UNARMORED_DEFENCE" />			
			<grant name="Agile Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK_AGILE_STRIKES" />			
			<grant name="Bardic Damage" type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK_BARDIC DAMAGE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Land's Aid" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook Rev. 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_LAND_LANDS_AID">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 3rd level, as a Magic action, you can expend a use of your Wild Shape and choose a point within 60 feet of yourself. Vitality-giving flowers and life-draining thorns appear for a moment in a 10-foot-radius Sphere centered on that point. Each creature of your choice in the Sphere must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 2d6 Necrotic damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. One creature of your choice in that area regains 2d6 Hit Points.</p>
			<p class="indent">The damage and healing increase by 1d6 when you reach Druid levels 10 (3d6) and 14 (4d6).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Magic Action">
			<description>You can expend a use of your Wild Shape and choose a point within 60ft form you. Any creature of your choice in a 10 foot-radius sphere from that point shall make a CON save DC{{land_aid:dc}}. On a fail, the creature takes {{land_aid:dice}}d6 Necrotic damages (save halves). Moreover, one creature of your choice within that area regains {{land_aid:dice}}d6 Hit Points</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="land_aid:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="land_aid:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="land_aid:dc" value="wisdom:modifier" />
			<stat name="land_aid:dice" value="2" />
			<stat name="land_aid:dice" value="1" level="10" />
			<stat name="land_aid:dice" value="1" level="14" />
		</rules>	
	</element>
	<element name="Natural Recovery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook Rev. 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_LAND_NATURAL_RECOVERY">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 6th level, you can cast one of the level 1+ spells that you have prepared from your Circle Spells feature without expending a spell slot, and you must finish a Long Rest before you do so again.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, when you finish a Short Rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your Druid level (round up), and none of them can be level 6+. For example, if you're a level 6 Druid, you can recover up to three levels' worth of spell slots. You can recover a level 3 spell slot, a level 2 and a level 1 spell slot, or three level 1 spell slots. Once you recover spell slots with this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Once per Long Rest, you can cast one 1+ Circle Spell you prepared, without expending the spell slot. In addition, once per Long Rest, after a Short Rest, you ragain expended spell slots of your choice, provided that the total level is equal or lower {{level:druid:half:up}}.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Nature's Ward" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook Rev. 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_LAND_NATURES_WARD">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 10th level, you are immune to the Poisoned condition, and you have Resistance to a damage type associated with your current land choice in the Circle Spells feature, as shown in the Nature's Ward table.</p>
			<h5>Nature's Ward</h5>
			<table>
				<thead><tr><td>Land Type</td><td>Resistance</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>Arid</td><td>Fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Polar</td><td>Cold</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Temperate</td><td>Lightning</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Tropical</td><td>Poison</td></tr>
			</table>	
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are immune to Poisoned condition and you gain Resistance to damage type associated to the choosen Land: Arid-Fire, Polar-Cold, Temperate-Lightning, Tropical-Poison.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Nature's Sanctuary" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook Rev. 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_LAND_NATURES_SANCTUARY">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 14th level, as a Magic action, you can expend a use of your Wild Shape and cause spectral trees and vines to appear in a 15-foot Cube on the ground within 120 feet of yourself. They last there for 1 minute or until you have the Incapacitated condition or die. You and your allies have Half Cover while in that area, and your allies gain the current Resistance of your Nature's Ward while there.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a Bonus Action, you can move the Cube up to 60 feet to ground within 120 feet of yourself.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As a Magic Action, you can expend one Wild Magic use to cause spectral tree branches to appear in a 15-foot cube, within 120ft form you. While in the cube, you and your allies gain the Half-Cover condition and the Land Ward resistance. The cube lasts for 1 minute or until you are incapacitated.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<!-- DAZZLING FOOTWORK EFFECTS -->
	<element name="Dance Virtuoso" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook Rev. 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK_DANCE_VIRTUOSO" />
		<sheet>
			<description>You have Advantage on any Charisma (Performance) check you make that involves you dancing.</description>
		</sheet>	
	</element>
	<element name="Unarmored Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook Rev. 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK_UNARMORED_DEFENCE" />			
		<sheet>
			<description>Your base Armor Class equals 10 plus your Dexterity and Charisma modifiers</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defence:dance" value="10" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defence:dance" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defence:dance" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defence:dance" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Agile Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook Rev. 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK_AGILE_STRIKES" />
		<sheet>
			<description>When you spend a Bardic Inspiration as an Action, Bonus Action or Reaction, you can make an Unarmored Strike as part of it.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Bardic Damage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook Rev. 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK_BARDIC DAMAGE" />
		<sheet>
			<description>You can apply the Dexterity modifier instead of the Strenght modifier to your Unarmed Strikes. You deal {{}}+{{dexterity:modifier}} Bludgeoning Damages. </description>
		</sheet>	
</elements>
